So we've loaded in the data and my first step will be to clean it up and explore it.
我们加载了数据 第一步是清理和探索数据
Data exploration is one of the most important parts of the ML workflow,
数据探索是机器学习工作流程的最重要环节之一
because it allows you to notice any initial patterns in data distribution
因为我们可以发现数据分布和特征的初始规律
and features that may inform how you proceed with modeling and clustering the data.
并根据这些规律继续建模和聚类数据
So above, I loaded in the CSV file as a county's DataFrame,
我在上面以 counties_df 的形式加载了 CSV 文件
and here I'm just printing out the number of rows and columns in that DataFrame.
我在这里输出了该 DataFrame 的行数和列数
Then on that DataFrame I'm calling.dropna across axis equals zero,
然后沿着 axis=0 对该 DataFrame 调用 .dropna
which means I'm dropping any rows that have any incomplete data,
表示我将删除任何数据不完整的行
and I'm saving this cleaned DataFrame as clean_counties_df.
并将整洁的 DataFrame 保存为 clean_counties_df
Then I'm printing out the shape to see how many rows of data I've lost.
然后输出形状 看看删除了多少行数据
So if I run this cell,
如果运行此单元格
I can see that I originally started with 3,220 datapoints and 37 columns.
可以看出 一开始有 3,220 个数据点 有 37 列
Then after this cleaning step,
在这个清理步骤之后
I can see that I've dropped two rows of data,
我删除了 2 行数据
and now I'm down to 3,218 datapoints.
现在有 3,218 个数据点
Okay. So this clean data is what I want to use as I continue to process this data below.
Ok 接下来继续处理数据时 我将使用这个整洁的数据
Next, I wanted to create a new DataFrame,
接着 我将创建新的 DataFrame
indexed by state county instead of individual indices.
按照 State-County 设定索引 而不是采用单键索引
So for each of the datapoints in our clean counties DataFrame,
对于 clean_counties_df 中的每个数据点
there is a state and a county value,
都有一个 State 和 County 值
and I can merge the two into a single string using a dash character.
我可以使用短划线将这两个字符串合并到一起
Then to index our DataFrame by this value,
然后 为了根据此值设定 DataFrame 的索引
I'm going to call clean_counties_df.index and set it to a new state dash county value.
我将调用 clean_counties_df.index 并设为新的 State-County 值
So this is the first step,
这是第一步
and I can see that now instead of having individual indices here,
现在这里不是单键索引
I'm indexing all of the data by its unique state county.
我用由 State 和 Country 两列构成的唯一键值来索引数据
But I haven't dropped any columns yet.
但是我还没有删除任何行
I can see that the state county corresponds to the index.
可以看到这个 state 和 county 对应于该索引
So now these two columns are actually redundant, and I can get rid of them.
所以现在这两列是多余的 可以删除
I'll also get rid of the census ID column,
我还将删除 Censusid 列
which doesn't really give me any meaningful information about these counties.
它并不能提供关于这些郡县的任何有意义信息
So that's exactly what I'm doing in this next cell.
在下个单元格中完成这项任务
I'm specifying the names of each of the columns that I want to drop,
我指定了要删除的每列的名称
and then I'm calling.drop on our clean counties
然后对 clean_counties_df 调用 .drop
DataFrame to create a new clean counties_df.
创建新的 clean_counties_df
If I display a few of these points,
显示几个数据点看看
now I have the DataFrame that I want,
现在获得了我想要的 DataFrame
indexed by state county,
它们按照 State-County 设定索引
and with numerical features as columns.
并且列是数值特征
I can see that I've actually gone from having 37 column values to 34,
列数从 37 个变成了 34 个
and I can print out the entire list of those feature values here.
我可以在这里输出整个特征值列表
So here's a list of all those column names in our clean counties_df.
这些是 clean_counties_df 中的所有列名称列表
We have the total population,
包括总人口
counts of men and women,
男性和女性人数
racial counts, labor counts and a bunch of other data here.
种族人数 劳动力人数 以及其他数据
Now that we've completed the step,
我们已经完成这一步
creating a nice clean counties DataFrame,
创建了整洁的 clean_counties DataFrame
we'll be able to do some interesting visualizations,
下面可以可视化这些数据
looking at the distribution of data over all of our counties.
看看所有郡县的数据分布情况
In fact, in this next step,
下一步
I want to compare some features and learn more about them.
我将比较一些特征 进一步了解数据
In the next cell, I'm going to display some histograms of
在下个单元格中 我将显示特征的直方图
our features which will show the distribution of datapoints over discrete feature ranges.
展示数据点在离散特征范围内的分布情况
So first, I'm making a list of features that I want to compare.
首先 列出我要比较的特征列表
In this case, I've chosen a bunch of transportation types.
我选择了几种交通类型
These are specifically recorded as commute types.
这些记录为通勤类型
Do people drive, carpool, take transit,
人们开车 拼车 坐公共交通
walk, or use another method when they commute to work?
步行 还是通过其他方式上下班？
From looking at my DataFrame,
从我的 DataFrame 中可以看出
I know that all these features are represented as percentages.
所有这些特征都用百分比表示
So the x-axis of these plots should be comparable.
所有这些图形的 x 轴是可比较的
So for each feature in this transport list,
对于 transport_list 中的每个特征
I'm going to create a single histogram grabbing the feature values in
我将创建一个直方图 按照名称
the clean counties DataFrame by name and
从 clean_counties_df 中获取特征值
specifying a number of bins to make in our histogram.
并指定直方图的区间数量
So here's one example histogram of people who mainly drive to work.
这个直方图表示开车上班的人
Each of these bandwidths describe some feature range.
每个区间都描述了某个特征范围
In this case, percentage points.
即百分点
So from about 0-5,
例如约 0-5
5-10, and so on ranges of percentage points.
5-10 等百分点范围
Then the y-axis is how many datapoints actually fall into these bins.
y 轴表示有多少数据点落入这些区间
So how many counties fall into a certain feature range.
表示有多少郡县落入特定的特征范围
There's some spread here.
数据有一定的分散性
So really I can see across counties ,people
可以看出 在各个郡县
commonly drive about 70-85 percent of the time.
人们通常有 70%-85% 左右的时间是开车上下班
There's even really small bumps close to zero percent of the time.
在接近 0% 左右还有一个小峰值
If I scroll down, I can see the same data for people who carpool in each county,
向下滚动 可以看到每个县的拼车数据
looks about like 10 percent of the time for the majority of counties.
大部分县的人约 10% 的时候拼车
I can see that for public transit and walking,
下面是公共交通和步行数据
and just intuitively, I think this makes sense.
直观地来讲 这些数据比较合理
I think the concentration of people who use
我认为使用公共交通和步行的人主要集中在大城市
public transit are probably in big cities where those systems are already built,
这些大城市的交通体系已经成熟
and it makes sense that that's a small percentage of the population.
并且只有小部分人群乘坐公共交通或步行也合理
Now, I want to note that I haven't sorted anything into clusters yet.
注意 我尚未创建任何聚类
I'm just looking at how people in our counties
只是查看郡县的人
classify their own transportation method to work.
是如何分类自己的通勤方式的
I can even change the number of bins if I want a more granular look,
甚至还可以更改区间数量
upping the number to get a more detailed description of this distribution.
查看更详细的数据分布情况
Now this is only an example for transportation data,
这只是一个交通数据示例
and there's a lot of other features in our dataset.
该数据集中还有很多其他特征
So as an optional exercise,
布置一道选择完成的练习
I'm challenging you to create a set of histograms of your own.
请创建一组你自己的直方图
Create a list of features that you're interested in
按照你感兴趣的一组特征
looking at and display the resulting plots.
绘制直方图
After that, you'll be asked to normalize this data
接下来 你需要归一化数据
in preparation for training a PCA model.
并为训练 PCA 模型做准备